nsidc.org 2007-02-07

# NSIDC Web Policy

Thank you for visiting the National Snow and Ice Data Center (NSIDC) Web site. Following is our policy on information that we track about visitors to our Web site, including the intent, maintenance, and possible uses of this information. 

### Automatically collected information

So that we may better serve our user community, we automatically collect the following information.  This information allows us to measure Web page usage so that we may appropriately format our site.  We do not collect personally identifiable information.

  * Domain name you are using (for example, “mycomputer.com”)
  * IP address from which you accessed our site
  * Type of browser software you are using 
  * Date and time of NSIDC Web site access 
  * Internet address of the Web site from which you linked to NSIDC
  * Pages visited on our site, and path taken to reach multiple pages
  * Status code indicating whether your browser was successful in rendering the page

### Personal information

We do not automatically collect personally identifiable information.  When you contact NSIDC via e-mail or by submitting a Web form, your  name and contact information may be stored so that we can respond to your specific request or provide you with future updates to requested data sets. 

NSIDC uses the Google search engine (an external search agency) throughout our Web site.  Please be advised that information collected when you use the Google search is determined by Google.  For more details on how Google collects identifiable information, see the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/privacy.html) on Google's Web site. 

### Cookies (information collected for tracking and customization)

A cookie is a small amount of information saved to a hard disk by a browser, as requested by the Web server.  Cookies are identifiers that facilitate the processing of Web forms.  NSIDC utilizes session cookies to enable the processing of our Web request and contact forms.  The information collected is only stored during a particular visit to our site.  We collect this information to improve service to you.

### Sharing and protecting information

We respect the privacy of our visitors and user community.  NSIDC may share the information described above with other government agencies as it relates to that agency or as required by law.  Information will not be shared with other agencies or entities as the law permits.  Visitors and users will only be contacted regarding specific questions submitted to NSIDC staff members, or regarding product and information updates to previously requested data or information.  At any time, you may request removal from such contact lists. 

### Accessibility

NSIDC strives to ensure the pages on this Web site are accessible to individuals with disabilities in accordance with [Section 508](http://www.section508.gov/) of the Rehabilitation Act. Some files on this Web site may be posted as Adobe Acrobat Portable Document Format (PDF) files. Adobe provides their [Acrobat Reader](http://www.adobe.com/products/acrobat/readstep2_allversions.html) software as a free download.

### Linking policy and disclaimer of endorsement 

As a service to our users, NSIDC links to many Web sites created and maintained by other public and private organizations. The presence of a link is not an NSIDC endorsement of the site. When users follow a link to an outside Web site, they are subject to the privacy and security policies of the owners/sponsors of those site(s). 

Please note that when you are accessing the "NASA Earth Observing Data Gateway at nsidc.org" (EDG), or the NASA "EOS Data Pool at NSIDC," you are subject to NASA's policies. You can link to NASA policies from the EDG and EOS Data Pool pages.

### Related privacy policy links

[United States Department of Justice Freedom of Information Act ](http://www.usdoj.gov/oip/)  

Last updated: 21 December 2006
